Finding Aid for the Bruce R. Payne Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Bruce R. Payne Papers
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0325
3.75 linear_feet
Biographical Note
Bruce Ryburn Payne was born on February 18,1874 in Mull Valley in North Carolina to Jordan Nathaniel Payne and Barbara Anne Eliza Warlick. He attended Trinity College (Duke University) in Durham, North Carolina receiving a baccalaureate degree in 1896 and a master’s degree in 1902. While earning his master’s degree Payne taught Latin and Greek at Durham High School. In 1902 he and his wife were offered scholarships to attend the Teachers College of Columbia University. In 1903 Payne received his second master’s degree the following year he was awarded a doctorate.
After receiving his PhD Payne taught for a year at William & Mary College as a professor of philosophy, while there he was elected to Phi Beta Kappa. In 1905 he became professor of secondary education and philosophy at the University of Virginia. Payne served as director of the summer institute for teachers and developed this program into a model for the continuing education of teachers during the summer months. The institute was to train young teachers and women who were not allowed to matriculate at the University of Virginia during the regular sessions. The program was rigorous and academically demanding and in being so demonstrated to skeptics the value of summer schools for teachers.
In 1911, Payne was recruited to Peabody College to be its first President and was given the task of starting a teachers’ college in Nashville, Tennessee from scratch. He immediately began planning for the construction of the first campus buildings and creating a vision for the new college. By 1913, plans were drawn up and the first buildings under construction. Sited across the street from Vanderbilt University Peabody College developed a love hate relationship that played out through the interactions of Payne and Chancellor James H. Kirkland. This sometimes acrimonious relationship lasted throughout the men’s lives.
Payne served as President of Peabody College till his death in 1937. In those twenty-six years he established the college as the premier location for teacher education in the south. Peabody’s growth of prestige can be directly linked to the careful caretaking of Bruce Payne during his tenure as leader of the institution. The faculty were cultivated and recruited with great care as were the relationships developed with the General Education Board and other granting agencies. When he died on April 21, 1937 of a heart attack in Nashville Payne had only recently returned from a trip north to meet with donors hoping to shore up the college during the difficult years of the Depression.
Payne was laid to rest at Mount Olivet Cemetery in Nashville, Tennessee. He left behind his widow Lula Carr, son Maxwell Carr Payne and a grieving college.
Scope and Content Note
The Bruce R. Payne Papers are comprised of nine boxes (3.75 linear feet) of correspondence and subject files. The papers are broken into three series. Series I: is the largest series (six boxes) and contains correspondence both outgoing and incoming with the outgoing organized by date and the incoming by name of sender. Another small sub-set is called Secondary and are carbons of letters sent to him for informational purposes.
Series II: Office of the President is comprised of subject files about topics of concern for Payne as President of Peabody College. These are arranged alphabetically in three boxes.
Lastly, Series III: Personal Records contains one folder about Bruce R. Payne’s finances.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence -Outgoing
    - January 23, 1912-July 4, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - July 15, 1912-December 26, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - January 15, 1913-October 1, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - January 14, 1914-November 3, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - December 4, 1914-December 28, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - January 16, 1915-December 27, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - December 20, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - January 29, 1917-August 24, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - February 19, 1918-August 22, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - October 18, 1919-December 1919 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - August 22, 1921-August 27, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - February 27, 1922-December 16, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - April 4, 1923-October 12, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - February 5, 1924-April 24, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - May 3, 1924-July 28, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - August 7, 1924-September 30, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - October 2, 1924-October 21, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - November 11, 1924-December 19, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - January 1, 1925-January 20, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - February 3, 1925-February 28, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - March 2, 1925-March 31, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - May 11, 1925-May 12, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - May 13, 1925-May 31, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - June 1, 1925-June 11, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - June 17, 1925-July 21, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - August 10, 1925-September 23, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - October 1, 1925-December 6, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - December 19, 1925-December 22, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - January 1, 1926-January 22, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - February 3, 1926-February 22, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - March 3, 1926-March 31, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - April 3, 1926-June 11, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - June 21, 1926-July 26, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - August 3, 1926-August 25, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - September 28, 1926-October 14, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - October 21, 1926-IMovember 24, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - December8, 1926-December 27, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - January 1, 1927-January 17, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - January 19, 1927-January 27, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - February 6, 1927-March 21, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - April 21, 1927-August 31, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - September 26, 1927-October 12, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - November 3, 1927-December 24, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - January 5, 1928-April 20, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - May 7, 1928-June 25, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - July 5, 1928-August 21, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - September 22, 1928-November 23, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - December 1, 1928-December 27, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - January 7, 1929-January 31, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - February 2, 1929-February 13, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - March 2, 1929-April 13, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - May 8, 1929-July8, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - August 29, 1929-October 16, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - November 4, 1929-November 25, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - December5, 1929-December 31, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - January 1, 1930-January 16, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - February 7, 1930-March 31, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - April 1, 1930-April 26, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - May 6, 1930-May 30, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - June 10, 1930-June 22, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence -Outgoing
    - July 1, 1930-July 28, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - August 11, 1930-September 22, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - October 2, 1930-November 21, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - December 11, 1930-December 20, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - January 10, 1931-January 28, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - February 2, 1931-february 27, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - March 11, 1931-May 28, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - June 22, 1931-June 29, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - July 3, 1931-August 25, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - September 3, 1931-September 29.1931 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - October 3, 1931-October 21, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - November 18, 1931- December 28, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - January 6, 1932-January 26, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - February 5, 1932-March 25, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - April 4, 1932-April 25, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - May 2, 1932-May 30, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - June 6, 1932-June 25, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - July 1, 1932-July 30, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - August 4, 1932-August 22, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - September 9, 1932-September 29, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - October 4, 1932-October 25, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - November 6, 1932-November 30, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - December 1, 1932-December 23, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - January 6, 1933-January 27, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - February 3, 1933-February 28, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - March 1, 1933-March 31, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - April 8, 1933-April 27, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - May 1, 1933-May 29, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - June 2, 1933-June 20, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - June 21, 1933-June 29, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - July 6, 1933-July 26, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - August 4, 1933-August 28, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - September 10, 1933-September 30, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - October 5, 1933-October 31, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - November 2, 1933-November 14, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - December 1, 1933-December 15, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - January 22, 1934-February 16, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - March 5, 1934-March 31, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - April 1, 1934-April 28, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - May 7, 1934-June 16, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - July 9, 1934-July 31, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - August 2, 1934-August 18, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - September 11, 1934-September 28, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - October 2, 1934-October 28, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - November 6, 1934-November 23, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - December 3, 1934-December 29, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - January 4, 1935-January 21, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - February 2, 1935-March 25, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - April 9, 1935-May 27, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - June 13, 1935-June 29, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - July 1, 1935-August 24, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - September 10, 1935-September 23, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - October 9, 1935-October 30, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - November 9, 1935-November 26, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - December 2, 1935-December 31, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence -Outgoing
    - January 4, 1936-February 28, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - March 5, 1936-april 27, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - May 7, 1936-May 30, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - June 3, 1936-June 22, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - July 6, 1936-July 17, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - July 18, 1936-July 30, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - August 5, 1936-August 22, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - September 4, 1936-September 30, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - October 5, 1936-October 22, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - November 2, 1936-November 19, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - December 18, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - January 8, 1937-February 12, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - March 18, 1937-March 30, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - April 6, 1937-April 16, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence -Incoming
    - Adams-Ames (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Anderson-Armstrong (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Arnett, Trevor (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Ault, O.C. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Bachman-Barnwell (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Barr-Beck (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Beeson, M.A. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Benedict-Blnstock (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Blshop-Bizzell (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Bogle, Sarah C.N. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Bolte-Bowle (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Braden-Brldges (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Brierley, W.W., 1928,1930-1931 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Brierley, W.W., 1933 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Brierley, W.W., 1934 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Brierley, W.W., 1935-1937 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Brlster-Broughton (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Brown-Browning (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Bryan-Butler (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Buttrlck-Byrns (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Caldwell-Capshaw (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Carney-Cawthon (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Chadwell-Clark (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Claxton-Clement (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Clifford-Combs (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Comer-Cooper (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Costello-Crawford (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Crlttenden-Currler (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Danlel-Davldson (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Davls-Dawson (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Dlcklnson-Dougherty (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Draper-Dwire (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Eason-Edgerton (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Edwards-Ellls (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Embree, Edwin E. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Erlkson-Evans (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Ewlng-Exner (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence—Incoming
    - Fair-Favrot (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Feakins-Fisher (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Fleming-Fouch (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Francis-Frankel (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Franklin-Frasier (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Galloway-Garvey (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Gibson-Goulding (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Gray-Guy (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Hall-Hanna (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Harding-Hardy (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Hargrove, H.L. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Harriban-Hegeman (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Hendrick-Highsmith (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Hill, H.G.-Hill, John (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Hill, Theda Buford Phillips-Hite (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Hoke-Hopkinson (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Hostetter-Hotz (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - House-Howse (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Hudson-Hurt (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Hutto-Hyde (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Inglis, James, November 22, 1926-September 29, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Inglis, James, October 3, 1927-December 27, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Inglis, James, March 23, 1928-December 31, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Inglis, James, August 12, 1929-May 31, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Irby, Nolen M. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Jack-James (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - James, George R. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Jarman-Jenks (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Jennings-Jessup (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Johnson-Johnston (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Jones-Juhan (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Keppel-King (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Kirkland, James H., September 15, 1911-December 1914 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Kirkland, James H., January 6, 1915-June 1, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Koenlg-Kohn (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Laird-Lane (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Lansill, John (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence -Incoming
    - Lawrence, William, September 14, 1909-December 6, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Lawrence, William, January 2, 1927-October 11, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Lawrence, William, October 16, 1929-November 4, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Lawrence, William, September 29, 1933-April 19, 1937, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Leathers-Leonard (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Lessenger-Letterdahl (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Libbin-Lloyd (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Lockwood-Lorenz (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Loventhal-Lyon (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - MacRae, Hugh, October 14, 1931-December 11, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - MacRae, Hugh, February 14, 1932-December 31, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - MacRae, Hugh, January 6, 1933-May 17, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - MacRae, Hugh, May 19, 1933-June 9, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - MacRae, Hugh, June 14, 1933-October 30, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - MacRae, Hugh, March 12, 1934-November 8, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - MacRae, Hugh, January 24, 1935-February 6, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Mahon-Martin (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Matherly-Maytubby (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - McAlister-McCuistion (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - McCune-McKellar (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - McKim, Mead & Whlte-McVey (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Mellon-Mims (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Minor, J. L., January 18, 1930-September 27, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Mitchell-Moorhead (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Morgan, Arthur E. -Morgan, Harcourt A. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Morgan, J. P., October 25, 1924-May 16, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Morgan, J. P., March 9, 1933-November 21, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Morris-Murphy (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Nadler-Newlen (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Norrell-Northcott (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Olds, Marshall, May 19, 1926-April 16, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Oster-Owens (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Palfrey-Payne (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Peabody, George Foster, March 31, 1925-December 6, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Peabody, George Foster, September 4, 1929-June 24, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Peabody, George Foster, October 28, 1932-September 27, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Peabody, George Foster, June 4, 1934-April 22, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Pearce-Pettit (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Phipps-Purdom (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Rabitte-Raulston (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Reeves-Reynolds (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Rice-Richey (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Robert-Robinson (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Rodman-Rogers (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Roosevelt-Rosier (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Ruml-Ryburn (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence -Incoming
    - Salley-Sarratt (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Satterlee, Herbert L., August 12, 1926-March 23, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Saucier-Servis (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Sharp-Sherrod (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Shoecraft-Sisson (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Smith-Southgate (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Spahn-Stevens (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Stewart-Stoddard (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, September 14, 1925-December 28, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, February 11, 1926-November 27, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, January 25, 1927-October 23, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, July 17, 1931-July 20, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Stone-Stubbs (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Suhrle, Ambrose L., April 7, 1927-undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Suhrle, Ambrose L., undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Survey-Suzzallo, December 23, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Suzzallo, Henry, January 7, 1928-November 28, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Suzzallo, Henry, January 13, 1929-January 24, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Suzzallo, Henry, March 17, 1930-June 3, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Taft-Taylor (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Teuton-Thorkelson (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Tldwell-Tiffett (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Tilton, Edward L., August 23, 1921-December 27, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Tlson-Tupper (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Turner-Twlnbridge (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Uffleman, Ivah W., February 7, 1930-March 29, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Valll, Evelyn Wilkes, April 15, 1929-October 12, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Vaill, Frederick S. -Vardell (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Waginer-Walker, Bradley (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Walker, Jestena M., August 11, 1922-December 17, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Walker, Jestena M., January 14, 1926-October 7, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Walker, Jestena M., October 5, 1933-October 14, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Walker, Jestena M., November 19, 1934-November 19, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Walker, Sydnor, May 9, 1925-July 10, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Ward-Weatherford (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Well-Whltley (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Wilcox-Wllllams (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Wllllamson-Wllson (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - WInchester-WrIght (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Unidentified (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence -Secondary
    - Inglls, James, August 9, 1926-November 24, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - McRae, Hugh, September 15, 1932-December 15, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - McRae, Hugh, February 27, 1933-October 6, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - McRae, Hugh, March 10, 1934-February 6, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - May 11, 1914-December 29, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - April 17, 1923-December 18, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - May 9, 1925-December 10, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - January 4, 1927-August 24, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - July 5, 1928-December 23, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - May 22, 1930-July 22, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - March 7, 1931-July 30, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - June 1, 1932-November 22, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - February 14, 1933-August 7, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - February 23, 1934-June 14, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - May 5, 1935-March 19, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Series II: Office of the President
  - Accreditation, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Administration Building-Elevations (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Campus and Proposed Buildings (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Chapel (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Commercial Education (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Confederate Memorial Hall (1 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Confederate Memorial Hall (2 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Confederate Memorial Hall (3 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Curriculum Budget, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Curriculum Budget, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - East Hall Dormitory (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Financial Needs--Campaigns (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Fundraising-Annuities (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Fundraising-Gifts and Pledges (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Fundraising -Peabody Educational Programs (1 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fundraising -Peabody Educational Programs (2 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Fundraising -Peabody Educational Programs (3 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Fundraising -Peabody Educational Programs (4 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Fundraising -Peabody Educational Programs (5 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Fundraising -Peabody Educational Programs (6 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Fundraising -Proposals (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Fundraising -Proposals (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - German Educators at Peabody (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Lawrence, Reverend William -Speech, February 29, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Lea, Luke (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Maytubby, Joel (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Series II: Office of the President
  - Memoranda to the Faculty, 1932-1933, 1935-1937 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - J. P. Morgan & Company (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Music Building Proposal (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - National Public Health Nursing (1 of 4) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - National Public Health Nursing (2 of 4) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - National Public Health Nursing (3 of 4) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - National Public Health Nursing (4 of 4) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, May 1912 (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, May 1912 (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, June-August 1912 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1926, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1931-1932, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Oil Companies’ Annual Reports (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Oil Companies’ Annual Reports (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Peabody, George Foster (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Peabody, George -Bust in Hall of Fame (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Rural Life School (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Rural Life School (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Series II: Office of the President
  - Series III: Personal Records
    - Scholarships, Fellowships, Loans (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Semi-centennial Proceedings (1 of 4) (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Semi-centennial Proceedings (2 of 4) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Semi-centennial Proceedings (3 of 4) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Semi-centennial Proceedings (4 of 4) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Social Religious Building (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Southeastern Council (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Southeastern Council (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Speakers (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Teacher Training (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Teacher Training (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Teacher Training -Statistics -Payne’s Research (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Teacher Training -Statistics -Payne’s Research (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Teacher Training -Statistics -Payne’s Writings (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Teacher Training -Statistics -Payne’s Writings (2 of2) (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Vanderbilt University (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Vespers (Box 9, Folder 17)